# Robert D McCabe

Full-stack software developer specializing in programming languages such as C#, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Python.

I have built projects such as a golf club shopping website to assist a customer in researching purchase options by brand, model, and price. This was created with HTML and CSS.

I also created a simulation of a blackjack game allowing a player to place bets and collect winnings similar to what would be experienced in a casino. This project was built with C# and .NET framework.

#### **Guitar Shopping Application** — *Project*

I also created a guitar shopping application in Python that helped users perform research and make purchase decisions based on their budget and brand preferences by model of guitar.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Prosper IT Consulting, Portland, OR** — Software Developer

September 2020 - April 2021

Created projects using various tools. Participated on a live projects part of a team using Python. I built a guitar shopping application that allowed a user to research by brand, price, and model to determine what guitar they wish to purchase.

#### Theater Vertigo

Participated as part of a team of developers at the Tech Academy in order to upgrade a local theater group's website. My particular task was to edit and add features to the blog author's page so that the theater could have reviews posted to their website. I used HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to beautify the site and C# razor pages to set up the pages. We used Azure in order to complete this project.

I also worked as part of a team to upgrade an existing website for a local theater group. I created a blog author section that allowed the theater to keep track of any reviews written on the performances at the theater.

5 Camden St. Apt D Johnson City, NY 13790

(607) 624-3853

rmccabe1023@gmail.com

GitHub:

github.com/rmccabe62

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/rmccabe62

Portfolio:

rmccabe62.github.io

#### **Nationwide Credit inc,** Endicott,NY — Debt Collector

September 2019 - December 2019

Tasks included placing outbound phone calls to consumers with past due credit card balances. Helped to set up payment arrangements for balances. Used SAP in performance of duties.

#### **Charter Communications**, Vestal, NY — *Billing Associate*

November 2018 - September 2019

Received incoming phone calls to assist cable, internet, and phone customers with billing issues and changes in service. Tasked with upselling of services to customers.

### **Millipore Sigma,** Saint Louis, MO — Customer Service

March 2018 - October 2018

Received incoming phone calls from government and education researchers – scientists to place orders for chemicals used in research. Used salesforce software in performance of duties.

# **Animal Medical Center of Mid-America,** Saint Louis, MO — *Call Center Agent*

July 2017 - March 2018

Received incoming phone calls from pet owners to schedule appointments for their pets. Duties included placing prescription refill orders for clients. Used Zendesk software in performance of tasks.

# **St. Louis Community College,** Kirkwood, MO — Computer Lab Assistant

January 2017 - June 2017

Used tracking software to grant access to college students to computer lab. Helped students with technical issues related to computer systems including troubleshooting of systems.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **The Tech Academy,** Portland, OR — *Certificate*

September 2020 - April 2021

Completed intensive coding boot camp with over 600 hours of training in software development. Acquired skills in computer programming such as C#, .NET framework, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Python.

## **St. Louis Community College**, Kirkwood, MO — Associates

August 2016 - May 2017

Pursuit of associates degree in software development. Did not graduate due to financial reasons.

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages:** 

C#, SQL,HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Python

IDEs: .NET Framework (Entity, and Core), and PyCharm(Python)

Team player, detail oriented, fast learner, and dedicated